# Jasper Drescher

Malmö, Sweden • (+31) 6 50128363 • jasperdre@gmail.com • jasperdre.com

## **Summary**

Gameplay Programmer with a passion for games and open-source projects. Involved in the development of gameplay, tools and engines for multiple games and platforms. Experience with project management and pipelines. Contributor to open-source projects and attendee of game events.

## **Skills**

Programming languages: C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, PHP, SQL

Software applications: Visual Studio, Snowdrop, Unity, Unreal Engine, Blender

## Experience

#### **Junior Gameplay Programmer**

Malmö, Sweden

**Massive Entertainment** 

August 2020 – present

- Develop gameplay and tools using Snowdrop and C++
- Collaborate in a cross-disciplinary team to iterate on gameplay for a new IP
- Organize a club for programmers within the studio to improve knowledge sharing

## Junior Gameplay Programmer (Intern)

Malmö, Sweden

Massive Entertainment

September 2019 - July 2020

- Developed gameplay and tools using Snowdrop and C++
- Collaborated in a cross-disciplinary team to ship features on time
- Developed multiple Title Updates for Tom Clancy's The Division® 2
- Developed a Free Trial version of Tom Clancy's The Division® 2
- Developed the largest expansion for Tom Clancy's The Division® 2

#### **Junior Software Developer**

Arnhem, The Netherlands

CortexArts

September 2014 – August 2019

- Developed tools using Unity, Java and C#
- Developed physics-based gameplay mechanics using Unity and C#
- Developed dynamic websites using PHP, SQL, HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Participated in Dutch Game Garden Incubation workshops
- Created 3D art assets using 3DS Max, Blender and Adobe Photoshop

Waiter

Vlissingen, The Netherlands

**DOK 14** 

July 2018 – September

2018

**Retail Clerk** 

Arnhem, The Netherlands

December 2014 – March 2015

Jumbo Supermarkten

### Education

**Bachelor of Science in Creative Media and Game Technologies**Breda University of Applied Sciences
2020 GPA 3.29/4.0

Breda, The Netherlands
September 2016 – July

## **Projects**

Tom Clancy's The Division® 2: Warlords of New York Tom Clancy's The Division® 2 Free Trial Tom Clancy's The Division® 2 Stellar Survivor

Unreal Engine, C++ Sep 2018 - Jul 2019

An FPS tower-defense survival game developed with fellow students at Breda University of Applied Sciences.

### **Drivinity**

Custom engine, C++ Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

An anti-gravity racing game developed using our own engine with fellow students at Breda University of Applied Sciences.

## **Awards**

### **Best Programming Year 2**

IGAD Game Awards, Breda University of Applied Sciences June 2018

• Winner Best Programming for Drivinity.